Nitish Prabhu Kota

nitish.prabhu26@gmail.com | +1(682)-283-5267 | github.com/nitishprabhu26 | linkedin.com/in/NitishPrabhuKota

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 3+ years of professional Full-Stack Web Development experience. Strong technical skills in designing, developing, testing, debugging, and maintaining complex websites; and training staff. Graduating from The University of Texas at Arlington, looking for Full-Stack Web Developer/Cloud Computing full time opportunities starting from May 2021.

EDUCATION

University of Texas at Arlington

Master of Science in Computer Science

(GPA: 3.6/4.0) Arlington, TX

Graduating in May 2021

- Major in Big Data Management, Databases and Cloud Computing; Artificial Intelligent Systems.
- **Related Courses:** Web Data Management, Artificial Intelligence I, Machine Learning, Advanced Topics in Database Systems, Data Mining, Software Testing, Software Engineering, Python Programming, Computer Networks.

NMAM Institute of Technology

(GPA: 7.83/10.0) KA, INDIA

Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communication

May 2016

SKILLS

Programming Languages: C, C++, PHP, Python, JAVA, SQL.

Frameworks: Angular JS, Angular 2/5/9, React JS, Flask, Laravel, Bootstrap 4/5.

Web Technologies: JavaScript, HTML/HTML 5, CSS 3, TypeScript, Jasmine, Karma, RESTful Web Services, jQuery,

XML, Google API's, JSON.

Database: MySQL, Google Cloud Datastore, MongoDB.

Cloud Services: AWS, Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud Platform, IBM Cloud (Bluemix).

Tools / Software: Visual Studio Code, Eclipse IDE, GitHub, Git, Jenkins, VSTS, Jupyter Notebook.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer - INFOSYS LIMITED, Mangaluru, India Software Engineer

May 2017 - July 2019

Oct 2016 - May 2017

- Managed cross-functional team of 10 in 3 locations (London, Mumbai and New York), ranging from entry-level analysts to vice presidents, and collaborated with business development, data science, and operations.
- Launched Miami office with lead Director and recruited and managed new team of 10 employees; grew office revenue by 200% in first nine months (representing 20% of company revenue)
- Designed training and peer-mentoring programs for the incoming class of 25 analysts in 2017; reduced onboarding time for new hires by 50%
- Organized and advertised quarterly networking events with 500+ participants in six cities across California.
- Overhauled the obsolete legacy source code of two production applications, resulting in increased usability and reduced run time performance by 50%

Software Engineer Intern/Trainee - INFOSYS LIMITED, Mysuru, India

May 2016 – Oct 2016

 Designed training and peer-mentoring programs for the incoming class of 25 analysts in 2017; reduced onboarding time for new hires by 50%

ACADEMIC/PERSONAL PROJECTS

Cloud Computing – Python/Flask Web Application (AWS Elastic Beanstalk, MS Azure, IBM Bluemix)

- Developed Python/Flask Web applications to perform various SQL queries on the USGS earthquake dataset.
- Hosted it on Amazon Web Services, Microsoft Azure, and IBM Cloud platforms.
- Implemented caching using Redis, load balancing and auto-scaling to support high load traffic and faster execution of
 queries, hence improving the system performance by 30%. Performed Load testing using Apache JMeter.

Social Distancing and Facemask Detection Monitoring System – (Python, OpenCV, COCO Dataset, YOLO v3)

• Implemented a model and trained it on COCO dataset from scratch, to detect if the people are maintaining social distance using **YOLO v3 Algorithm** and **OpenCV**. Developed Face recognition Model to analyze images & identify facial landmark.

Burger's on Grill: Dynamic Responsive Restaurant website – (Laravel, PHP, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap 5) (Demo)

• Designed and Developed two Dynamic Responsive Web Applications using PHP and Laravel, respectively. Implemented role-based access with secure authentication, Order and Payment gateway etc. Hosted it online with SSL certificate.

CERTIFICATIONS AND AWARDS

- Certified JAVA Developer Diploma in JAVA from Manipal Institute of Computer Education (MICE).
- Awarded with INSTA Award by Service Offering Head at Infosys for my contributions in Google SDM project.
- Secured 2nd place in the Organizational level Hackathon organized by Infosys Limited, presented a project titled Image to HTML conversion using Machine Learning and Tensor flow (Python).
- Won 2nd place in the events: ROBOTHON and DARE TO DESIGN at National Level Tech Fest Tech-Nidarshan.